Guide to the Records of the Faculty of Arts and Science 1968-1986 RG 21.0
New York University Archives
Records of the Faculty of Arts and Science
1968-1986
RG 21.0
New York University Archives
13.0 linear feet 13 linear feet (13 boxes)
The collection contains deparment files created by the Faculty of Arts and Science dating from 1968 to 1986.
New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged topically.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
Departmental Files
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains departmental files of the Dean's office of the Faculty of Arts and Science.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Faculty of Arts and Science (FAS) consists of the undergraduate College of Arts and Science (CAS), the Graduate School of Arts and Science (GSAS), and three disciplinary divisions: the Division of the Humanities, the Division of Science and the Division of the Social Sciences.
Founded in 1832, the CAS formed the foundation of the University. GSAS was added in 1886, awarding the second earned doctorate in the United States.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
This collection is in
off-site storage
.
Provenance
This collection was transferred from the Dean's office of the Faculty of Arts and Science to the University Archives in 1993.
Correspondence.; Reports.; Universities and colleges |x Administration.; Universities and colleges |x Faculty.
- Series I: Departmental Files
  - Applied Science, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226136 5
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Applied Science, 1974-1975, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Applied Science PhD Proposals/SED (2), 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Applied Science PhD's, (Current) (2), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Basic Medical Sciences, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Inactive File-Search for Biology Chairman, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Biology: Search for Chairman, 1980, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Biology, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Program in Biomedicine and Law, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Biology File #1, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Biology File #2, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Applied Science PhD, Proposal/SED (3), 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Biology Department (5), 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Comparative Literature 9/1978 - 8/1979, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226137 3
  - Comparative Literature 9/1976 - 8/1978, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Comparative Literature 9/1975 - 8/1976, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Departments/Computer Science, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Courant Institute Grant Proposal Vol. I (book), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Courant Institute Grant Proposal Vol. 2 (book), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Department of Economics (1), 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Institute for Economic Analysis (1), 1975, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Economics Starr Center, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Economics Starr Center, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Search for an Economics Chairman, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Economics, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Economics, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ecomonics, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - English, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - English Department, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - English, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - English, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Expository Writing, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Expository Writing, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - English, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Search for English Department Chairman, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - English: Expository Writing Program/Educational Testing Service, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Fine Arts Department: Search for Chairman, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Environmental Health Science Department, 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - French and Italian Department, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226618 2
  - French and Italian Department, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - French and Italian Department, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - French and Italian Department, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - French and Italian Department, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Institute of French Studies, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - German, 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - History Department, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - History Department, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - History Department, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Search for History Chairman, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Search for History Chairman, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - History, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - History, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - History, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Philosophy, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Journalism, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Journalism, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Journalism, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Journalism, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Journalism, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Linguistics, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Linguistics, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Linguistics, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Dean Turner, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Liberal Studies, 1974, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226619 0
  - Manhattanville, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Search for Mathematics Chairman, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Mathematics up to 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Medieval and Renaissance Studies, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Metropolitan Studies, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Master of Arts and Liberal Studies, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Museum Studies, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Museum Studies, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Museum Studies, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Museum Studies, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Music Department Search for Chairman, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Music, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Music, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Music, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Near Eastern Languages and Literature, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Near Eastern Languages and Literature, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Near Eastern Languages and Literature, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - NYU Abroad (General File) (up to 1979), 1972-1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - NYU in France, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - NYU in France, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - NYU in London (up to 1979), 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - NYU in Spain, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - NYU in Spain, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - NYU in Spain, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - NYU in Spain, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Philosophy, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Philosophy, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226620 8
  - Physics Department Tech Services, De Santis, John, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Physics, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Physics, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Physics, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Poetics Institute, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Politics Department (2), 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Politics, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Politics, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Politics, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Politics, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Anthropology Dept, Program Proposal, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226621 6
  - Anthropology Dept, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Applied Science Dept (3), 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Applied Science Dept (1), 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Applied Science Dept (2), 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Applied Science: PhD Evaluation and Budget Proposal, to 1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Applied Science Dept: Search for Chairman, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Applied Science Dept: Visiting Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Biological Sciences Doctoral Review: General File, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Biology Department: Confidential Material, 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Biology Department: Development, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Biology Department (3), 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Biological Sciences Doctoral Review: Sackler Institute, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Biology: Doctoral Review, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Biology Department: Advisory Committee, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Biology Department, 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Biology Department: Brooklyn Polyechnic Institute (PINY), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Chemistry Department, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Chemistry Department, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Classics Department, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226622 4
  - Comparative Literature Department (1), 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Comparative Literature Department (2), 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Comparative Literature: Search for Chairman, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Computer Science: Lab Fees, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Computer Science Department, 1977-1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Economics: Starr Center, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Economics Department, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Economics: Starr Center, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Economics Department, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Economics Department, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Economics Department, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Economics: Institute of Economic Analysis (IEA), 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Economics: Institute of Economic Analysis (IEA), 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - English Department, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226623 2
  - English Department, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - English Department, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - English: Expository Writing Program Review, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Fine Arts Department, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Fine Arts Department, 1971-1979 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Search for Fine Arts Chairman, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - French and Italian Department: Institute of French Studies, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - French and Italian Department: Institute of French Studies, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - French and Italian Department, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - French and Italian Department, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - German: Deutsches Haus, 1976-1981 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - German Dept: Search for Chairman, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - German Dept, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - History Department: Search for Chairman, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Linguistics Dept: Search for Chairman, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Medieval and Renaissance Studies, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Metropolitan Studies Evaluation, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Manhattanville Program, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Mathematics Dept: Search for Chairman, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Mathematics Dept, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Manhattanville Program, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Metropolitan Studies Program Evaluation, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Metropolitan Studies Program, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - History Department Future Development, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04227207 3
  - History Dept. Women's History Program, 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - History Dept. History Morse Project, 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - History Dept., 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - History Dept. Archival Training Project, 19801983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - History Dept. American Civilization Program, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - History Dept. Public History, 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - History Dept., 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Institute of Fine Arts, 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Institute of Fine Arts, 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Journalism Department: Science and Environmental Reporting Program [SERP], 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Journalism Dept., 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Journalism Dept., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Journalism Dept., 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Journalism Dept. Search for Chairman, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Linguistics Department, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Linguistics Dept., 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Linguistics Dept.: Search for Chairman, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Linguistics, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Applied Science Dept., 1979-1987 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04227208 1
  - Biology Department./ Dental School, Confidential, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - English Depaartment, 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Classics Department, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Center for War, Peace News Media, 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - French and Italian Departments, 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - History Dept., 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Department of Slavic Languages and Literatures, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Linguistics Department, 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Journalism Workload, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Institute of French Studies, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Kevorkian Center, 19861987 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04227209 9
  - Department of Politics, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Draft: GSAS Planning, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Grey Art Gallery, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Grey Art Gallery, 1976-1978 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Grey Art Gallery, 1968-1978 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - FAS Budget Five Year Plan, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Sunrise Semester, 1979-1983 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Performance Reviews Planning, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Grey Art Gallery Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subsidiary Ledger, 1985-1988 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Status of Expense Budget Dept/Sub Code, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Government Grants and Contracts, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Status of Expense Budget Dept/Sub Code, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Subsidiary Ledger Summary, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Changes in Funds by FG, Type, Sch., Dept., 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Changes in Funds by FG, Type, Sch., Dept., 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Changes in Funds by FG, Type, Sch., Dept., 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04227210 7
  - Miscellaneous, 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Budget Closeout, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Fall Enrollment Projections, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Graph of Income vs. Expense, 1983-1985 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Expository Writing Program: Student Work, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - French and Italian Department Budget, 1977-1983 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04227211 5
  - Journalism/ ATEX, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Forms Transmitted for Deposit, 1979-1983 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Anthro. HC, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Applied Science HC, 1977-1979 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - English HC, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Classics HC, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Fine Arts HC, 1978-1983 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - German HC, 1978-1981 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - History HC, 1976-1983 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Politics Institute CFG, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Summer Institute in History CFG, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Applied Economics CFG, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Economics and Statistic CFG, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Summer Program in Arabic, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - NY CLACS, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Music-E. Brody CFG, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Politics HC, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Slavic HC, 1978-1983 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - NELL HC, 1978-1981 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Philosophy HC, 1977-1980 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Chemistry Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Anthropology Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Biology Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - CLACS Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - CV Starr Center for Applied Science, 1982-1984 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Classics Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Summer Session, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Spanish and Portuguese, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - English Budget, 1981-1983 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Comp. Lit. Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Womens Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - History, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Journalism, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Fine Arts, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Institute of French Studies, NYU/France, Maison, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - German, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Economics, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Computer Science, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - CLACS, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Classics, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Comp. Lit., 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Chemistry, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Biology, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Anthropology, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - French and Italian, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - English, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Werner Brandt Fellowship Fund, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - FAS Budgets, 1978-1981 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Sociology HC, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Chemistry HC, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Psych HC, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Spanish and Portuguese HC, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Physics Dept. CFG, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Mathematics, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - Metropolitan Studies, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - Music, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 57)
  - Manhattanville, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 58)
  - Linguistics, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 59)
  - MALS, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 60)
  - Sociology, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Politics, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 62)
  - Physics, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 63)